Guide to the Cayuga County sugar beet industry records, 1961-1979.
Cayuga County sugar beet industry records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cayuga County sugar beet industry records, 1961-1979.
3249
Gould P.(Gould Patchin), Colman 1926-,
3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Newspapers, Photographs, Printed Materials, Publications, Research Materials, Scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Photocopies of newspaper clippings concerning the Maine Sugar Industries, Inc., the Finger Lakes Sugar Beet Growers Association
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Photocopies of newspaper clippings concerning the Maine Sugar Industries, Inc., the Finger Lakes Sugar Beet Growers Association, and unsuccessful attempts to develop a sugar beet industry in central New York. Includes photographs, bulletin preparation materials, correspondence, notes, and a research proposal about the project. Also includes two films: "The Root of Progress" and "Introducing Sugar Beets," tables, scrapbooks, and additional correspondence, photographs, and bulletins.
Also, "Finger Lakes Sugar Beet Growers Association and Pepsi-Cola Company Present the Story of Beet Sugar. Authors: C. L. Swanson and J. T. Bugbee Through the Courtesy of Texaco's Magazine Lubrication."
SUBJECTS
Names:
Colman, Gould P.1926- ,; Bateman, Theodore,; Bugbee, J. T.; Swanson, C. L. W.; Finger Lakes Sugar Beet Growers Association.; Maine Sugar Industries, inc.; Pepsi-Cola Company.
Subjects:
Sugar beet industry--New York (State)--Cayuga County.; Sugar beets--New York (State)--Cayuga County.; Agricultural development projects--New York (State)--Cayuga County.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Material was collected by Gould Colman and Theodore Bateman.
CONTAINER LIST
- Clippings from Maine papers Re: Sugar Beet Industry (Box 1)
- Sugar Beet Feasibility Study, 1963 (Box 1)
- Sugar Beet Questionnaires, 1968 (Box 1)
- Oneida Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Oswego Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Madison Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Genessee Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Seneca Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cortland Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Onondaga Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Sugar Beet Project (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Cayuga Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Herkimer Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Monroe Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Ontario Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Livingston Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Yates Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous Documents (Box 1)
- The Groundnut Affair (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Documents Regarding Sugar Beet Production (Box 1)
- Sugar Beet Paper (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence and Documents of Gould P. Colman (Box 1)
- Howard Bateman's Extension Letters, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Empire Sugar Grower Letters (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Grower Association Letters (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous Documents and Letters (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
- Sugar Beet Newspaper Clippings (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Documents and Letters (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
- Photos, Slides, and Negatives (Box 2, Folder 4)
- The Cayuga County, New York Sugar Beet Story (Box 2, Folder 5-8)
- Miscellaneous Documents (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Sugar Beet Business Requirements (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Photographs (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
- The Need for New and Continuing Research (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Need for an Educational Effort with Farmers (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Research and Educational Guidance (Box 2, Folder 15)
- The Immediate Need (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Interested Parties Team Up For Action (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Tentative Agenda for Meetings with Sugar Beet Demonstrators (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Sugar Beet Journal, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Correspondence of Jim Lawrence (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Miscellaneous Documents (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Sugar Beet Guidelines for Growers, Jan. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Legal Documents (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Sugar Beets, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Photographs (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Film Script (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Sugar Beet Directory (Box 2)
- Sugar Beet Mailing List, 1965-1968 (Box 2)
- Film: Introducing Sugar Beets, 1963 (Box 2)
- Scrap Book 1966-1970 (Box 3)
- Scrap Book 1971-1972 (Box 3)
- 1974 Finances (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Finances 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Press Releases File Copy (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Press Releases File Copy Pt 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Minutes (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Finances 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Finances 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)